Thea Olivia Yusuf

theaolivia.mail@gmail.com ⊠ https://teaolivia.github.io/

+46 73 3953 018

https://github.com/teaolivia https://www.linkedin.com/in/theaolivia/ in

Software/Data Engineer

I am a data/software engineer from Indonesia but currently based in Stockholm, Sweden. I strive to deliver best end-to-end solutions to my stakeholders who are data analysts and data scientists that work for decision making engine by focusing on data quality, freshness, throughput and infrastructure with Klarna since last 2 years. Before I worked on various backend and even frontend projects which build my software design fundamentals.

Experience

Klarna Bank AB

June 2020 -Data Engineer

- · Speeded up decisions with serve 4 variables in just 1 week by maintain and improve serving layer of Klarna data processing powerhouse written mainly in Java, consisted of AWS Lambda and DynamoDB ingestion, Kafka realtime ingestion and RabbitMQ that run upon AWS EC2 which is containered by Docker
- Shortened pipeline processing time from 24 to 12 hours by decommissioned an old realtime database system and create new model result with PosgreSQL that executed with Airflow which send to AWS Redshift, carefully deployed with Jenkins and some Ansible script with some Python3 automation scripts
- · Increased stakeholder engagement by 30% and less onboarding time so that we don't have to reexplain the meaning and proper usage of certain variables by rebuilt internal team onboarding website using ReactJS and some GraphQL
- Increased team productivity and data correctness by 20% by participate in on-call rotations to ensure quality of the pipeline service through monitoring with Splunk, QlikSense and DataDog
- Increased speed of market acquisition by 15% by doing ETL job which is providing data points for analyst in order to find merchant performance by extracted external API and centralised AWS Redshift using Python3 script, transformed the data by executing Airflow bagpipe to run PostgreSQL stored procedure to be loaded to QlikSense data dashboard

Software Engineer January 2020 - June 2020

- · Improved candidate acquisition amount from 10 to 20% of daily batch by designed and built an internal extension of Lever, a popular HR management software which is written in Python3 with Flask framework containered with Docker
- · Speeded up recruiters accountability from 1 month follow-up time gap to the slowest is 2 weeks by did ETL job of Lever external data and clean up internal data that is the result of the ETL job and stored in AWS RDS

Freelance Software Developer

January 2018 - December 2020

- Acted as a software consultant for small to medium businesses
- · Designed and implemented RESTful API using Flask which is written in Python server for a project which develop a coupon sharing social media web application, also orchestrate to deploy on cloud service which was AWS EC2

Projects

2019 viral.in, https://github.com/teaolivia/viral.in and https://github.com/teaolivia/viralin-client An app which combined discount coupon and social media. Designed and implemented RESTful API with Flask and ReactJS for frontend. Containered with Docker which ran upon AWS stack

2017 AquaAesthetic, https://github.com/keychera/AquaAesthetic Object-oriented Programming course project in Java, incorporated Java Spring and JUnit for testing

Accomplishments

2021 Participant in Google Hash Code 2021

Participant in ACM-ICPC 2017 Regional Contest in Southeast Asia region

2016 Selected as one of the finalists team in Facebook Indonesia Developer Challenge

Education

Bandung Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

September 2011 - April 2018

Thesis Malware Detection in Application Layer with Machine Learning Methods

Courseworks Algorithm and Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Distributed and Parallel Systems, Databases,

Machine Learning